（来找我）
（近了）
（找到你了）
你以为能躲过我的眼睛吗
You think you could hide from me, did you?
看到上面写了什么吗 上面写着我找到你了
Did you read what it said? It said found you.
- 但是没写我会挠… - 塞穆尔 小贝
- It didn't say tickle… - Samuel. Bee.
够了
That's enough.
- 你肯定不想闹得太热了 - 是的
- You don't want to get overheated. - I'm not.
你确定吗
You're sure?
很好 因为轮到我了
Good. Because now it's my turn!
- 爸爸 帮帮忙 - 你叫帮忙
- Dad, help! - You need help?
当然了 我可以帮忙挠你
Oh sure, I can help tickle you.
我觉得这只脚丫子底肯定很好挠
I think the bottom of this feet might be very ticklish.
该上床了 小贝
Time for bed, Bee.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 爱你 妈妈 - 我更爱你
- Love you, Mommy. - Love you more.
妈妈
Mommy?
- 就听一会 - 谢谢
- Just for a little while. - Thanks.
妈妈
Mommy.
我们回家后能玩娃娃吗
Can we play dollies when we get home?
我觉得如果你帮我洗碗
Well, I think if you help me with the washing up
- 我整个下午都能陪你玩娃娃 - 塞姆
- I can play dollies with you all afternoon. - Sam.
太好了
Yes!
塞姆
Sam.
早上好 塞姆
Good morning, Sam.
- 早上好 埃斯特 - 早上好
- Good morning, Esther. - Morning.
你好啊 小贝
Hey there, busy Bee.
塞姆 我就想问问…
Sam, just wondering…
我订的娃娃准备好了吗
if you got that order of mine ready yet?
我的店里每天都有客人来
I got customers coming into my store everyday
问起你的娃娃
asking about your dolls.
你明天可以让你儿子过来拿了 维克
You can send your son over tomorrow, Vic.
都准备好了
They're ready.
哈雷路亚
Well, hallelujah.
看来祈祷真的是能灵验的
I guess prayers do get answered, don't they?
没错
They do.
对 太谢谢你们了 祝你们有个愉快的周日
Oh right… well, thank you so much. You all have a good Sunday.
- 你也是 - 祝你今天愉快
- You have a good day too. - You have a lovely day.
你们先上
In you get.
该死
Damn it!
主语用语
Language.
有辆车来了 我能不能招呼他们停下来
There's a car coming, why don't I wave it down
看看他们能不能帮我们
and see if we can get some help.
不用不用 我能行
No, no, no, no. I got it.
我去捡
I'll get it.
小贝
Bee!
不
No!
《安娜贝尔2：诞生》
（12年后）
（圣尤斯塔斯女孩之家）
东南西北
B-l-u-e
好了 选个方向
Okay. Pick a number.
琳达
Linda?
北
Four.
好
Okay.
你很快就能结交新的朋友
You will soon make new friends.
给我测
Do my now.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我只是希望我们能去个新家
I just wish you and me were going to a new home
而不是新的孤儿院
instead of a new orphanage.
苏宝贝也这么想
Sweet Sue thinks too.
能有个家当然好了
It would be nice to have a home.
是啊 但是…有你才行
Yeah, but… only if you're there.
我不想去没有你的地方
I don't want to go anywhere you're not.
那我们发誓
So, let's swear.
如果有人要领养我们其中一个 另一个也要一起
If someone wants one of us, they get both of us.
好 我发誓
Okay. I swear.
好
Good.
我也是
Me too.
你知道我最喜欢苏宝贝哪一点吗
You know what I like most about Sweet Sue?
什么
What?
她看上去和你一样
She looks just like you.
还有多远 神父
So, how much further is it, Father?
圣母圣父圣子啊 你比孩子们还激动 修女
Jesus, Mary and Joseph. You're worse than the children, sister.
马林斯夫妇愿意收留我们简直是上帝的礼物
The Mullins agreeing to take us in was a gift from God.
要得到礼物当然会激动了
What kind of person isn't excited about getting a gift?
我得提醒一下 如果你们刚去
I should mention don't be alarm if you…
没怎么见到马林斯太太 不要紧张
don't see much of Mrs Mullins at first.
她…身体不好
She… has a condition.
她前几年遭遇了一场意外
You see, she was in an accident years ago.
如果有需要的话 你们几个女孩尽量帮帮她
You girls would do well to help her if need be.
真大
It's big.
珍妮丝 你需要帮助吗
Janice. You need help?
不用 谢谢 我可以的
No, thanks. I can manage.
修女
Sister.
她不幸患有小儿麻痹症
She's one of the unfortunate ones with that polio outbreak,
但她每天都在变得更坚强
but she's getting stronger everyday.
我保证 她不会成为你的负担
She won't be a burden, I promise you.
马林斯先生 你先带女孩们转转吧
Mr Mullins, why don't you show the girls around?
我把她们的行李搬下来
I can unload their belongings.
先看看里面吧
We'll start inside.
谢谢你 神父
Thank you, Father.
这简直就像城堡一样
Wow. This is an amazing castle.
那我们肯定就是公主了
Which obviously makes us the princesses.
这是我们的新孤儿院吗
This is our new orphanage?
我觉得这样就算我们永远不会被领养也行吧
I think this is fine if we're never being adopted.
还有电视
There's a TV.
电视已经坏了 广播还可以用
The television no longer works, the radio however does.
这房子真大啊
This goes on forever.
是的 我们可能需要地图才能找到路
You're right. We're going to need a map to find our way around.
孩子们 这边
Girls, this way.
正如你们所见 餐厅完全能容纳
As you can see, the dining room is more than adequate
我们所有人
to accommodate all of us.
快看这里
Wow. Look here.
咱们别走散
Let's stay together.
我和马林斯太太一起住在这里
Mrs Mullins and I stay in here.
楼下除了这间房 其他地方都随便用
Fell free to use the rest of the downstairs as you see fit.
你们的房间在楼上
Your rooms are upstairs.
马林斯先生
Mr Mullins.
珍妮丝和我能住在楼下吗
Is there someway Janice and I can maybe stay down here?
我也想要一起
Me too.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
这是我几年前为我妻子安装的
I installed it years ago for my wife.
好久没用了 但是还可以用
Hasn't been used in ages, but it works fine.
试试 小珍
Try it, Jan.
如果你不试 我来
If you don't, I will.
往上扳是往上
Up is up
往下扳是往下
Down is down.
但是除非你
But it won't work…
系上安全带 才会动
unless you click the seat belt in.
像这样
Like this.
很简单
Simple.
谢谢你
Thank you.
下一个轮到我
I get to go next!
字幕
Wow. Nice.
我猜这就是我们的房间了
I guess this is ours.
我们俩睡这边
Let's take that side.
凯特和蒂尔尼可以睡这两张
Kate and Tierney can have these.
那琳达和我呢
What about Linda and me?
别急 珍妮丝 这房子很大 还有别的卧室
Relax, Janice. This is a big house, there are other bedrooms.
我和琳达为什么不能睡在这边
Why can't Linda and me have those over there?
好吧 那凯特和蒂尔尼睡哪边
Okay, but then, where would Kate and Tierney sleep?
这里真干净
This is neat.
我要这张床
I got this one.
锁上了
Locked.
就让它继续锁着吧
And it stays that way too.
珍 这边
Hey, Jan. In here.
你想睡双层床吗
You wanna bunk beds?
- 夏洛特修女 我们能… - 主啊
- Hey sister Charlotte, can we… - Oh Lord.
请赐予南茜不把别人
Please bless Nancy with the wisdom
吓出心脏病
to not give people their heart attacks.
抱歉
Sorry.
你有什么急事
What is your emergency?
我们能出去探索吗
Can we go exploring?
先帮马赛神父收拾好你们的东西再…
Help father Massey with your things first and then…
但是马林斯先生坚持要我们去
But Mr Mullins insist that we go.
但那不代表你就不用…
But that doesn't mean you don't have to…
你也知道马赛牧师这个人
You know how Father Massey is.
我们只会给他碍手碍脚
We'll only get in the way.
- 好吧 - 她同意了
- Fine. - She said okay!
但是一定要互相照应
But look out for one another.
你一起来吗 珍
You coming, Jan?
等一会吧
Maybe in a little while.
那
Well.
我也陪你吧
Maybe I'll stay too.
因为你同情我吗
Because you feel sorry for me?
你保证过不会对我有差别对待的
You promised you wouldn't treat me any differently.
好吧
Okay.
回头见
See ya!
主啊 谢谢你将我们聚在一起
Dear lord. Thank you for bringing us all together.
赐予我们食物
Bless this food for our use,
庇佑我们的心灵
and us to thy service.
让我们的内心充满感激
Fill our hearts with grateful praise.
荣耀归於圣父 从今日到永远
And help us give you glory each day through
我们的主 阿门
Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
不好意思
If you'd excuse me.
卡萝尔
Carol.
别管闲事
Keep to your own business.
如果我在睡梦中死去 希望主能带走我的灵魂
And if I die before I wake, I pray the Lord my soul to take.
上帝啊 请保佑琳达和我能找到新家
Please, God. Help Linda and me find a good home
让我们能一直一起
and keeps us together.
- 让我们能成为真正的姐妹 - 还有亲爱的父母
- So we finally be real sisters. - With good loving parents.
最好也和我们一样讨厌家庭作业
That hate homework because we do.
但是就算他们不喜欢 也行吧
But, even if they don't, that's okay too.
阿门
Amen.
（来找我）
（这里）
南茜
Nancy.
卡萝尔
Carol.
你们在里面吗
Are you guys in here?
天父 请原谅我将要犯下的罪孽
Forgive me, Father, for I am about to sin.
我听说马林斯先生就把妻子安置在这里
I heard this is where Mr Mullins keeps his wife.
她真的戴着面具吗
Does she really wear a mask?
是的 她看上去像个洋娃娃
Yeah, she looked like a doll.
马林斯太太
Mrs Mullins?
你在这里吗
You down there?
别闹了
Stop it.
我觉得他看上去人不错
I think he seems nice.
你为什么不去找珍妮丝 看看她在干什么呢
Why don't you go find Janice, see what she's up to.
为什么
Why?
这样你们好讨论男孩子吗
So you can talk about boys.
那你想讨论男孩子吗
Well, do you want to talk about boys?
真恶心 不想
Gross. No.
我想玩游戏
I want to play a game.
好吧
Okay.
那我们来玩捉迷藏吧
Let's play hide and seek.
你去躲 我们来找你
You go hide and we'll come look for you.
好
Okay.
那我们要去找她吗
So, are we going to look for her?
也许吧
Maybe.
保佑你
Bless you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我问了马林斯先生能不能把这个房间
I asked Mr Mullins if we could use this room
用做我们的新教室
for our new classroom
他慷慨地同意了
and he graciously agreed.
你要来帮忙吗
Would you like to help?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我想做告解
I have a sin to confess.
原谅我 夏洛特修女 我犯下了罪孽
Forgive me, Sister Charlotte, for I have sinned.
- 我已经 - 至少两星期
- It's been… - At least 2 weeks.
至少两星期没有做告解了
at least 2 weeks since my last confession.
楼上有个我不该进去的房间
There's this room upstairs I'm not suppose to go into.
但你还是进去了
But you did anyway.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
因为不然的话你为什么要来告诉我呢
Because otherwise why would you be telling me about it.
那扇门已经打开了
Well, the door was already opened.
我不知道为什么 因为马林斯先生明明锁了
I don't know how because Mr Mullins always keeps it locked.
我进去后看到一个小娃娃
When I went inside there was this little doll.
- 真的非常奇怪 - 珍妮丝
- And it was really strange. - Janice.
开始发生一些很奇怪的事
Weird things started to happen.
珍妮丝 听听你自己说的话
Janice, listen to yourself.
我经常怎么说
What do I always say?
罪孽就是罪孽 不管是什么罪
A sin is a sin no matter the context.
更重要的是你绝对不能不听马林斯夫妇的话
More importantly, you absolutely cannot disobey the Mullins.
我们才到这里 他们愿意让我们留在这里
We only just got here and they're doing a very generous thing
已经是非常慷慨了
by allowing us to stay with them.
如果他们决定不收留我们了
If they decide to no longer have us here…
我们都会被分开
we'll all be split up.
下次你如果还想不守规矩
So next time you're thinking of breaking a rule,
先想想那会不会影响到其他女孩
think of how that could've affect the other girls first.
你明白了吗
Do you understand me?
明白了 对不起 修女 是我没好好考虑
Yes. I'm sorry, Sister, I wasn't thinking.
没事 亲爱的
It's okay, love.
最为惩罚 你要做一次祷告
For your penance, pray 1 Hail Mary
并帮我收拾好三个箱子里的东西
and unpack 3 of these boxes.
你们在干什么
What are you guys doing?
收拾箱子
Unpacking boxes.
这地方太恐怖了
This place is so creepy.
那是什么
What was that?
你说什么
你怎么敢这样说
How dare you!
稻草人先生
Oh, Mr Scarecrow.
找到你了
Found you.
你躲得不是很好嘛
You're not very good at hiding.
年久失修 支架平衡坏了
Years of neglect have affected the counter balance.
好了 现在应该不会有穿堂风了
There. That should keep the draft out.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是在罗马尼亚拍的
That was taken in Romania.
那是个与世隔绝的修道院
At a convent of cloistered nuns.
她们和外界世界几乎没有联系
They have little contact with the outside world
但我和她们三个关系很好
but I became very close to these three.
那是玛利亚修女 那是安娜修女
That's Sister Maria. That's sister Anna.
那是卢西亚修女
And that's Ssister Lucia.
那是谁
Who's this?
我…我不知道 我觉得我应该没见过她
I… don't know. I don't think I even met her.
你还有什么需要吗
Is there anything else you need?
不用了 谢谢
No. Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
我喜欢他
I like him.
你要嫁给谁
Which one would you marry?
我不知道
Oh. I don't know.
我只能和每一个都交往试试才能知道了
I guess I'll just have to date all of them to find out.
你觉得他的眉毛怎么样
How do you like his eyebrows?
- 他的眼睛 - 他是不是很帅
- His eye. - Ain't he handsome?
马林斯太太到了晚上就会获得力量
Night time is when Mrs Mullins gets her powers.
所以她整天躺在床上 但到了晚上…
That's why she's in bed all day. But at night…
她想去哪里都行
she can go wherever she wants.
她必须要出去 这样才能进食
She needs to so she can feed.
如果你和她对视 你便会死去
And if you look directly at her you'll die.
为了让你看她 她会一直叫你的名字
And to get you to look, she'll keep saying your name
一遍又一遍 直到你实在忍不住回应
over and over till you can't stand it!
南茜 南茜
Nancy. Nancy.
- 南茜 - 不 不
- Nancy… - No. No.
南茜
Nancy.
不
No.
她准备好进食了
She's ready to feed.
卡萝尔 卡萝尔
Carol. Carol.
卡萝尔
Carol.
我们不该起来闹的
Hey, we're not suppose to be up.
反正你也会醒
Well, you'll do it to.
他为什么不回应她
Why isn't he answering her?
- 是她 - 别看她
- It's her. - Don't look at her.
不
No!
不 拜托 拜托 拜托
No. Please please please…
拜托
Please.
她走了
She's gone.
她走了 她走了
She's gone. She's gone.
怎么了
What's going on?
出什么事了
What on God's earth?
- 夏洛特修女 - 马林斯太太
- Sister Charlotte. - Mrs Mullins.
她刚刚在这里 我们听到了
She was here. We heard.
在这个房间里 她刚刚就站在这里
In this room, she was standing right over there.
谁
Who?
是你的妻子
Your wife apparently.
她们说她刚刚站在这里
They said she was just in here.
那不可能
Oh, that's impossible.
我的妻子已经瘫痪在床很多年了
My wife hasn't been able to walk for years.
孩子们 孩子们
Girls. Girls.
我们继续学习吧 好吗
Let's go back to our studies, okay?
你没事吧 南茜
You okay, Nance?
你昨晚真的看到马林斯太太在你们的房间吗
Did you really see Mrs Mullins in your room last night?
是的 我们发誓我们当时盖着床单…
Yes. We swear we were under the cover and…
南茜 别说了
Nancy. Stop it.
昨晚是我们自己吓自己 你也清楚
We just freaked ourselves out last night, you know that.
马林斯太太
Mrs Mullins?
夏洛特修女
Sister Charlotte.
能麻烦你帮我拿一杯水吗
Could I trouble you for a glass of water?
当然了
Of course.
能听到这房子里重新焕发生机真好
It's good to hear some life again.
我躺在这里太久了
I've been cooped up here so long
都忘了人声是怎么样的了
so long I forgotten what that sounded like.
这照片真好看
What a lovely picture.
不幸的是 她很小
She was taken from us
就离开了我们
at an early age… unfortunately.
你能转过去一会儿吗 修女
If you could turn away for a moment, Sister.
当然了
Yes, of course.
我对你女儿的事感到很遗憾
I'm very sorry to hear about your daughter.
但想到她会在天堂等着你们 我们也会宽慰不少
But we find comfort in knowing she waits for you in heaven.
我也希望是这样
I wish that were true.
我的天啊
Oh my Gosh.
你不应该进来的
You shouldn't be in here.
你也是
Well, neither should you.
这房间到底是谁的
Who's room is this anyways?
马林斯夫妇曾经有个女儿
The Mullins had a daughter.
这是她的
It was her's.
曾经有一个
Had one?
我觉得她死了
I think she died.
我觉得那个音乐也是她放的
And I think that was her playing the music too.
别吓我了
Stop trying to scare me.
我没有 我说的是真的
I'm not. It's the truth.
那我们为什么还在这里
Then why are we in here?
- 我们该走了 - 不
- We should leave. - No.
琳达
Linda.
怎么了
What is it?
我们不该来这里
We shouldn't be in here.
好吧
Okay.
我马上就走
I'll leave in a minute.
我要走了
Well, I'm going.
（亲爱的日记 今天我回家了）
是谁
Who's doing that?
你好
Hi.
你是马林斯夫妇的女儿 是吗
You're the Mullins' daughter… aren't you?
你出什么事了
What happened to you?
你能帮我吗
Will you help me?
你需要什么
What do you need?
你的灵魂
Your soul!
夏洛特
Charlotte!
夏洛特修女
Sister Charlotte!
不
No.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
给她一点空间
Give her some space.
孩子们
Girls.
珍妮丝现在有点低落
Janice is feeling a little down right now.
我们需要尽我们所能支持她
So, we need to do what we can to support her.
我觉得她现在需要的是时间
Time I think is all she needs.
她能重新走路的 对吗
She'll walk again, right?
还不知道
We'll have to see.
你应该睡一觉
You need sleep.
这样能帮你恢复
That's going to help you with the healing.
我不能留在这里 夏洛特修女
I can't stay here, sister Charlotte.
我们不能留在这里
We can't stay here.
我们得离开这里
We need to leave.
离开
Leave?
去哪里
And go where?
我们无处可去了
There isn't anywhere else for us to go.
我不是摔下楼梯的
I didn't fall down those stairs.
是有东西把我丢下去的
Something threw me.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你经常说
You always say that
即使我们看不到上帝 我们也能
even though we can't see God we can…
我们也能感受到他的存在
we can feel his presence.
在这个房子里我感受到了另一种存在
In this house I feel a different kind of presence.
怎么样的
What kind?
邪恶的
An evil one.
它要来找我
It's coming after me.
要得到我的灵魂
Coming after my soul.
你的灵魂
You soul?
因为我是最弱的
Because I'm the weakest.
不 亲爱的
No, darling.
听着
Listen.
恶魔只会盯上那些信仰不坚定的人
The devil preys on those weak in faith,
而不是身体羸弱的人
not weak of flesh and bone.
你和我们一样强 珍妮丝
You are as strong as any of us, Janice.
甚至更强
Stronger.
你很安静 塞穆尔
You're quiet, Samuel.
我觉得让那些女孩
I think it was a mistake…
住在这里是个错误
to bring the girls here.
为什么
Why?
那个女孩
The girl…
那个摔下来的女孩
The girl that fell.
也许她不是摔下来的
Maybe she didn't fall.
也许
Maybe…
那是个意外
It was an accident.
就是这样
That's all it was.
经常会有意外
Accidents happen.
已经沉寂了12年
It's been quiet for 12 years.
你应该努力接受那些女孩们的存在
You should try embracing the presence of the girls…
而不是把她们吓跑
instead of frightening them away.
你很快就会好起来的
You'll be better soon.
我不觉得
I don't think so.
这次不会了
Not this time.
但你得好起来
But you have too.
你说我们会找到一个新家
You said we'll find a new home.
现在没人会要我了
No one is going to want me now.
我只会是一个负担
I'll just be a burden.
但你发过誓我们俩会永远一起
But you swore we'll stick together.
我收回
I take it back.
也许不会有人收养我了
Maybe I won't get adopted.
会的
You will.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为你很特殊
Because you're special.
你会被一个很美好的家庭收养
You're going to get adopted by a nice family somewhere
她们会非常非常宠爱你
and they're going to spoil you so much.
你会有很多很多娃娃
You're going to have so many dolls that…
你甚至连名字都起不过来
you won't even be able to name all of them.
我当然可以
Sure I can.
珍妮丝一号
Janice one.
珍妮丝二号 珍妮丝三号
Janice Two. Janice Three.
琳达 该上床睡觉了
Linda. Time for bed.
你不上楼来吗
Won't you come upstairs?
我不想一个人睡
I don't want to sleep alone.
来
Here.
带上贝卡
Take Becca.
这样
This way,
我就能一直陪着你
I'll always be with you.
那就把苏宝贝给你
Then, you should have Sweet Sue.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还记得在来到这里之前
Remember before all of this.
我们在孤儿院时经常半夜溜出去
When we used to sneak around the orphanage at night,
然后去食品储藏间吃巧克力
And ate all the chocolate in the pantry.
马赛神父一直以为我们害老鼠
Father Massey was convinced that we had mice.
主啊 请你洗涤我灵魂的罪孽
Oh Lord, please cleanse my soul of my sins
清楚我们房中的…
and cleanse our house of…
- 那些老鼠 - 那些老鼠
- these mice. - these mice.
不管发生什么
Whatever happens…
我总是会想到我们一起做的那些事
I'm thinking always all those things we did together.
晚安 琳达
Good night, Linda.
晚安 珍妮丝
Good night, Janice.
晒点太阳对你有好处
A little sunlight will do you some good.
我觉得晒太阳也没法解决我的问题
I don't think the sunlight can fix what's wrong with me.
你绝对不能放弃希望
You mustn't give up hope.
希望是一个家园
Hope is a home onto itself.
走进其中 就会得到庇佑和保护
Dwell in it and it will protect and keep you.
这是出自《圣经》的哪一部
What book of the Bible is that from?
出自《夏洛蒂之书》
The book of Charlotte.
但这不说明这话没有道理
But that doesn't make it any less so.
你自己在这里没事吧
Are you okay here?
太阳光感觉的确不错
The sunlight actually feels kind of nice.
我就说吧
I told you.
太低了
That's too low.
夏洛特修女
Sister Charlotte?
不不不
No, no, no!
不 求你了
No! Please!
珍妮丝
Janice!
怎么回事
What's going on?
我出不来
I couldn't get out.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
我很担心珍妮丝
I'm worry about Janice.
几个晚上之前她还很想走
A few nights ago she wanted to leave.
为什么她想走
Why she want to leave?
可能因为这个地方太疯狂了
Probably because this place is off the wall.
她告诉我马林斯的女儿盯上了她
She told me the Mullins's daughter was coming for her.
马林斯夫妇有一个女儿吗
The Mullins' had a daughter?
她很久以前就死了
She died a long time ago.
那她是见鬼了吗
So, she's seeing ghost?
声音轻一点
Keep your voice down.
那她是见鬼了吗
So, she's seeing ghost?
我猜是吧
I guess.
你们也看到了些什么
Well… You guys saw something.
那不是鬼
That wasn't a ghost.
只有死人才能算是鬼
Ghost can only be of dead people.
那你们看到的东西怎么解释
How does that explain what you saw?
除非那真的是马林斯太太
Unless it really was Mrs Mullins.
或者…是什么东西想吓你们
Or… something was just trying to scare you.
你们几个讨论得还挺起劲的
You guys are doing a good job with that on your own.
珍妮丝可能只是在想办法
Janice is probably just looking for ways
让我们给她特殊待遇
to justify us treating her differently.
我不觉得
I don't think so.
你当然不觉得了
Of course you don't.
等你长大了就知道了
You'll know what I mean when you're older.
上床去吧
Now go get to bed.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
没什么
Nothing.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
很好看
It's nice.
不算什么最得意之作
It's not my finest work.
你看起来有心事
You seem troubled.
也许我能帮你
Maybe I can help.
我不觉得
I don't think so.
有时候可能你只是需要说说
Talking about the things that bothers us sometimes…
困扰你的事
all the help we need.
是珍妮丝
It's Janice.
她表现得很奇怪
She's acting funny.
表现得很奇怪
Acting funny?
她说
She says…
她见到了你的女儿
she's seen your daughter.
我的女儿
My daughter…
已经去世很久了
has been dead for a very very long time.
我知道 但是…
I know, but…
珍妮丝进了她的房间
You see, Janice went into her bedroom.
什么
She what?
她知道她不该进去 但是…
She knows she wasn't suppose to but…
- 她找到了一个娃娃 然后… - 什么娃娃
- she found this doll and… - What doll?
穿白裙子的那个
The one in the white dress.
那不可能
That's impossible!
那娃娃已经藏起来了
That doll was hidden away.
她绝对不能靠近那个娃娃
She mustn't go near that doll!
你明白了吗
You understand me?
（找到你了）
珍妮丝 我和你说了不要进那个房间
Janice, I told you not to use that room.
请不要夺走我的阳光
*Please don't take my sunshine away*
待在这里
Stay here.
马林斯先生
Mr Mullins.
马林斯先生 你没事吧
Mr Mullins, are you okay?
准备上床睡觉吧 姑娘们
Go get ready for bed, girls.
我得找马林斯太太谈谈
I need to speak to Mrs Mullins.
琳达 你在干什么
Linda. What are you doing?
这个娃娃
This doll.
它伤害了珍妮丝 还杀了马林斯先生
It's hurting Janice and it killed Mr Mullins.
我要丢掉它
I'm getting rid of it!
琳达 我们回去吧
Linda, let's go back.
琳达
Linda?
不
No!
那是什么
What is that?
管他是什么 快跑
Who cares! Run!
珍妮丝 珍妮丝 我扔掉它了
Janice. Janice. I got rid of it.
我扔掉那个娃娃了
I got rid of the doll.
珍妮丝
Janice.
- 怎么了 - 珍妮丝在哪里
- What's going on? - Where is Janice?
- 我不知道 - 去找她
- I don't know. - Go find her.
快点
Hurry!
出什么事了
What's going on?
不
No!
不 把那东西离我远点
No! Get that thing away from me!
它回来了
It's back.
我知道它回来了
I know it was back.
什么东西
What is it?
邪恶
Evil.
恶魔
The devil itself.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
塞穆尔和我 失去我们的女儿后
After Samuel and I… lost our daughter
我们终日祈祷 只要能让我们
we prayed and promised our devotion to
再次见到我们的爱女
whatever power that would allow us to
不惜求助了一些不明不白的力量
speak or see our beloved girl again.
一开始那些联系很微弱
It started small, the contact.
但的确是她
But it was her.
我们的小贝
Our busy Bee.
我们知道是她
We know it was her.
她想要我们允许她进入娃娃的身体
She wanted permission to move into the doll
这样她就能永远陪着我们了
so she could be with us forever.
（拜托了）
我们答应了
We said yes.
然后那些联系开始变得强烈起来
And that's when it became stronger.
很快我们就能看到她了
Soon we can actually see her.
虽然只有短短几瞥 但那也够了
Only in fleeting glimpses but it was enough.
我们最爱的小贝
Our beloved Bee.
我们亲爱的
Our darling.
安娜贝尔
Annabelle?
即使我没法抱住她
Even though I couldn't hold her.
能像以前一样 真的很安心
It was comforting to start the past activity again.
但是我们马上发现 那根本不是安娜贝尔
But we soon realised it wasn't our Annabelle at all.
你是我的阳光 我唯一的阳光
*You are my sunshine, my only sunshine*
当天空灰暗
*You make me happy*
是你让我快乐
*when skies are gray*
亲爱的 你不知道
*You'll never know dear*
我有多爱你
*how much I love you*
请不要夺走我的阳光
*Please don't take my sunshine away*
埃斯特
Esther?
Esther.
我的…眼睛…
My… eye…
那是一个恶魔
It was a demonic presence.
它利用安娜贝尔控制我们
And it was using our Annabelle to manipulate us
让它得到想要的灵魂
into giving it soul it couldn't have.
它想夺走我的灵魂
It tried to take mine.
但是塞穆尔去了教堂
But Samuel reached out to the church.
他们拯救了我的灵魂
They saved my soul
但是那个恶魔仍然附身在娃娃身上
but the evil was still attached to that doll.
所以我们把它锁起来
So we locked it away
用圣经将它禁锢起来
where it could be surrounded by the word of God.
它沉寂了这么多年
It was quiet for all these year.
我以为恶魔已经被控制住了
I thought the evil was contained.
我们以为帮助那些女孩是在为自己赎罪
We thought helping the girls could be our penance.
但是现在看来 却让它如愿以偿了
But we end up giving it just what it wanted.
你是我的阳光 我唯一的阳光
*You are my sunshine, my only sunshine*
当天空灰暗 是你让我快乐
*You make me happy when skies are gray*
- 亲爱的你不知道 - 珍妮丝
- *You'll never know dear* - Janice.
我有多爱你
*how much I love you*
请不要夺走我的阳光
*Please don't take my sunshine away*
她能走路
She can walk.
只有我们 珍妮丝
It's just us, Janice.
是时候停止所有的罪孽了 卡萝尔
Time to cease from sin, Carol.
夏洛特修女 夏洛特修女
Sister Charlotte! Sister Charlotte!
是…是珍妮丝
It's-it's Janice.
- 她…她… - 看看她都做了什么
- She's… She's… - Look what she did!
- 卡萝尔 快去求助 - 好
- Carol, call for help. - Okay.
- 待在一起 - 好
- And stay together. - Okay.
他们马上来了 我们去安全的地方
They're on their way. Let get somewhere safe.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
我们不能就这么把她丢在这里吧
We can't just leave her here, can we?
马林斯太太
Mrs Mullins?
孩子们
Girls.
我们快走
Let's go. Now!
修女 原谅我的罪孽
Forgive me, Sister, for I have sinned.
- 夏洛特修女 夏洛特修女 - 快跑
- Sister Charlotte! Sister Charlotte! - Run!
琳达
Linda!
快跑 蒂尔尼 去找人帮忙
Go, Tierney! Get help!
或者…
Or…
你可以帮我
you can help me.
车
The truck!
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
- 关门 关门 - 快点
- Close the door! Close the door! - Come on!
快走 快走
Go! Go.
- 不 - 不 快啊
- No! - No! Come on!
好了
Okay.
不
No!
我在努力
I'm trying!
- 发动不起来 - 我在努力
- It's not starting! - I'm trying!
伙计们
Guys!
- 伙计们 伙计们 - 什么 什么
- Guys! Guys! - What? What?
稻草人
The scarecrow.
什么稻草人
What scarecrow?
什么…
What…
- 凯特 - 快点
- Kate. - Come on!
快点 快跑
Come on! Run!
卡萝尔
Carol?
什么
What?
不 不
No! No!
南茜 我打不开门 锁上了吗
Nancy, I can't get the door open. Is it locked?
你那边能打开吗
Can you get it from your side?
伙计们
Girls.
南茜
Nancy?
不
No.
不 不
No. No.
主啊 帮帮我 主啊 救命
Lord, help me. Lord, help.
救…
Help…
卡萝尔 是我
Carol, it's me.
是我啊
It's just me.
快走
Now, come on.
琳达
Linda.
她疯了
She's loon.
不
No!
夏洛特修女
Sister Charlotte?
你知道我最喜欢苏宝贝哪一点吗
You know what I like most about Sweet Sue?
她看上去和你很像
She looks just like you.
琳达
Linda?
你在哪里 琳达
Where are you, Linda?
琳达
Linda?
琳达 出来玩啊
Linda, come out and play.
找到你了
Found you!
你发过誓如果我找到家 你要和我一起
You swore if I found a home you'd come too.
你知道违背誓言会有什么下场
You know what they say about breaking a swear.
你会直接下地狱
You go straight to hell.
珍妮丝
Janice!
原谅我
Forgive me.
不
No!
放我出去
Let me out!
快走
Go!
- 夏洛特修女 - 夏洛特修女
- Sister Charlotte! - Sister Charlotte!
有发现吗
Anything?
恐怕没有
I'm afraid not.
还是找不到那个女孩
Still no sign of the girl.
但是她年纪这么小…
But at her age…
能跑多远
how far could she'd gone?
别担心
Don't worry.
我们会找到她的
We'll find her.
这个房子已经受到净化
This house is blessed.
这里的邪魔已经不复存在了
Whatever evil was here is no longer.
但是…
But…
那个娃娃
The doll.
那只是恶魔的载体
It was a conduit for the evil.
恶魔已经离开了
That evil has moved on.
现在这个娃娃只是个娃娃
Now the doll is just a doll.
所以…
So…
谁想要这个
which one of you gets this?
你感觉怎么样
How are you holding up?
我没事
I'm okay.
那时的珍妮丝不是她自己 而是…
You know, that wasn't Janice back there. That was…
别的东西
something else.
我知道
I know.
（圣约阿希姆孤儿院）
你们好 欢迎
Hi there. Welcome.
我们直接进去吧
Let's go right inside, shall we?
她一般不怎么说话 有些安静
She mostly keeps to herself, that can be a bit quite,
但她是个可爱的女孩
but she's a lovely girl.
她只是经历了太多事
She's just been through a lot.
我觉得你们会喜欢她的
I think you will love her.
你好
Hello.
有人来见你 亲爱的
There's someone here to see you, sweetie.
这两位是希金斯先生和希金斯太太
I want to introduce you to Mr and Mrs Higgins.
那你肯定是
And you must be…
- 安娜贝尔 - 安娜贝尔
- Annabelle. - Annabelle.
这名字真美
What a lovely name.
我们给你带了礼物
We brought you a present.
希望你喜欢娃娃
I hope you like dolls.
（12年后）
- 你听到了吗 - 听到了
- Did you hear that? - Yeah.
怎么回事
What is it?
待在这里
Stay here.
不 不 不 等等
No, no, no! No, wait.
没事的 没事的 亲爱的
It's okay. It's alright, sweetheart.
我就是去看一看
I'm just going to take a quick look.
快报警
Call the police.
- 安娜贝尔 - 你好 妈妈
- Annabelle? - Hi, Mom.
约翰
John.